Guide to the Eleanor Clark Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1876-1988; Series II; 5; (12 boxes)
  - General Correspondence
    - Evans, Walker, 1965, undated (Box 29, Folder 374)
    - "F" General, 1933-1985 (Box 29, Folder 375)
    - Fahy, Jack, undated (Box 29, Folder 376)
    - Fitzgerald, Robert, 1977-1981, undated (Box 29, Folder 377)
    - Forum, 1981 May 20 (Box 29, Folder 378)
    - "G" general, 1930-1978 (Box 29, Folder 379)
    - The Georgia Review, 1979-1984 (Box 29, Folder 380)
    - Goirand, Yvonne Henri, 1927-1985, undated (Box 29, Folder 381-383)
    - Gregory, Horace, 1936-1981 (Box 29, Folder 384)
    - Guilloux, Louis, 1938 February 22 (Box 29, Folder 385)
      Includes photographs
    - "H" General, 1936-1980 (Box 29, Folder 386)
    - Harvard University, 1979 May 9 (Box 29, Folder 387)
    - Heuser, Alan, 1982 (Box 29, Folder 388)
    - Horgan, Paul, 1970-1980 (Box 29, Folder 389)
    - Horton, Philip, 1936-1939 (Box 29, Folder 390)
    - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1941 (Box 29, Folder 391)
    - Houston Post, 1970 October 21 (Box 29, Folder 392)
    - Hudson Review, 1974 February 7 (Box 29, Folder 393)
    - Institute of Living, 1962-1965 (Box 29, Folder 394)
    - "J" General, 1956-1982 (Box 29, Folder 395-396)
    - Jessup, Eunice, 1929-1972 (Box 30, Folder 397-399)
    - Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1966 (Box 30, Folder 400)
    - "K" General, 1978 January 25 (Box 30, Folder 401)
    - The Kenyon Review, 1939-1980 (Box 30, Folder 402)
    - Klay, Andor, 1976 October 21 (Box 30, Folder 403)
    - Kubie, Lawrence S. (Lawrence Schlesinger), 1960-1970 (Box 30, Folder 404)
    - "L" General, 1944-1985 (Box 30, Folder 405)
    - Léger, Dorothy, 1965-1977 (Box 30, Folder 406)
    - Lockwood, Helen, 1934-1968 (Box 30, Folder 407)
    - Longley, Edna, 1976-1977 (Box 30, Folder 408)
    - Lyman, Frederick, 1915-1931, undated (Box 30, Folder 409-410)
    - "M" General, 1955-1981 (Box 30, Folder 411)
    - MacLeish, Archibald, 1977-1979 (Box 30, Folder 412)
    - MacNeice, Louis, 1939-1942 (Box 30, Folder 413-415)
    - MacNeice, Louis, 1939-1942 (Box 31, Folder 416-417)
    - MacNeice, Louis (outgoing), 1939-1962 (Box 31, Folder 418-421)
    - Marlowe, Sylvia, 1953-1982 (Box 31, Folder 422)
    - McCall's, 1965-1972 (Box 31, Folder 423)
    - McClatchy, J. D.
    - Meredith, William, 1964-1970 (Box 31, Folder 424)
    - Milch, David, undated (Box 31, Folder 425)
    - Modern Occasions, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 426)
    - Morante, Elsa, 1955-1964 (Box 31, Folder 427)
    - Moustakis, Christy, 1937-1980 (Box 31, Folder 428)
    - Murray, Harry, 1978-1980, undated (Box 31, Folder 429)
    - "N" General, 1964-1985 (Box 31, Folder 430)
    - Naginski, Charles, 1938-1939 (Box 31, Folder 431-433)
    - Nevins, Robert, 1972-1983 (Box 31, Folder 434)
    - New Directions Publishing Corp, 1938-1984 (Box 31, Folder 435)
    - New England Review, 1984, undated (Box 31, Folder 436)
    - The New Leader, 1974 December 12 (Box 31, Folder 437)
    - The New Republic, 1934-1935 (Box 31, Folder 438)
    - New York Magazine, 1974 December 23 (Box 31, Folder 439)
    - New York Review of Books, 1965-1974 (Box 31, Folder 440)
    - New York Times, 1964-1978 (Box 31, Folder 441)
      Includes letters from Clark to NYT
    - The New Yorker, 1969-1984 (Box 31, Folder 442)
    - "O" General, 1932-1977 (Box 32, Folder 443)
    - "P" General, 1935-1984 (Box 32, Folder 444-445)
    - Palmer, John, 1960-1984 (Box 32, Folder 446)
    - Pantheon Books, 1970-1975 (Box 32, Folder 447)
    - Partisan Review, 1937-1980 (Box 32, Folder 448)
    - Patterson, Lloyd, 1939-1940 (Box 32, Folder 449-451)
      Includes third party correspondence
    - Peyre, Henri, 1982-1985 (Box 32, Folder 452)
    - Phelps, Charles Henry (grandfather), 1930 (Box 32, Folder 453)
    - Phelps, Mrs. Charles Henry (grandmother), 1934 (Box 32, Folder 454)
    - Porter, Katherine Anne, 1937-1981 (Box 32, Folder 455-459)
    - Powers, Edward J., 1969-1975 (Box 32, Folder 460)
    - "R" General, 1950-1981 (Box 32, Folder 461)
    - Random House (Firm), 1959 (Box 32, Folder 462)
    - Rice, Ethel P., 1933-1943 (Box 32, Folder 463)
    - Rukeyser, Muriel, 1933-1970 (Box 32, Folder 464-466)
      Includes photograph
    - "S" General, 1950-1985 (Box 33, Folder 467)
    - Salmagundi, 1973 September 9 (Box 33, Folder 468)
    - Saturday Evening Post, undated (Box 33, Folder 469)
    - Scully, Stephen, 1981-1982 (Box 33, Folder 470)
    - Sender, Ramón [José?], 1942-1943 (Box 33, Folder 471)
    - Sewanee Review, 1965-1974 (Box 33, Folder 472)
    - Shenandoah, 1968 December 17 (Box 33, Folder 473)
    - Simon and Schuster, Inc., 1937 February 18 (Box 33, Folder 474)
    - Solow, Herbert, 1934-1940 (Box 33, Folder 475)
    - Southern Review, 1938-1975 (Box 33, Folder 476)
    - Stallworthy, Jon, 1983, undated (Box 33, Folder 477)
    - Steegmuller, Francis, 1951-1992 (Box 33, Folder 478)
    - "T" General, 1934-1983 (Box 33, Folder 479-480)
    - Tanning, Dorothea, 1967-1980 (Box 33, Folder 481)
    - Tate, Allen, 1944-1977 (Box 33, Folder 482)
    - Tematy, 1963 (Box 33, Folder 483)
    - Theta Sigma Phi, 1970 August 10 (Box 33, Folder 484)
    - Tinkle, Lon, 1975 February 20 (Box 33, Folder 485)
    - Trilling, Lionel, 1939-1975 (Box 33, Folder 486)
    - Udall, Stewart L., undated (Box 33, Folder 487)
    - United States Information Service, 1962 (Box 33, Folder 488)
    - University of Kentucky. Library, 1980 (Box 33, Folder 489)
    - "V" General, 1980-1984 (Box 33, Folder 490)
    - Vassar College, 1930-1985 (Box 33, Folder 491)
    - Venture, 1965 (Box 33, Folder 492)
    - Vogue, 1964-1965 (Box 33, Folder 493)
    - Vonnegut, Kurt, 1971 August 3 (Box 33, Folder 494)
    - "W" General, 1963-1985 (Box 33, Folder 495)
    - W.W. Norton & Company, 1937 August 19 (Box 33, Folder 496)
    - Wadsworth Publishing Company, 1967 December 6 (Box 33, Folder 497)
    - Warren, Ana F., 1983 (Box 33, Folder 498)
    - Warren, Gabriel (son), 1969-1988, undated (Box 33, Folder 499-500)
    - Warren, Gabriel, 1969-1988, undated (Box 34, Folder 501-504)
    - Warren, Gabriel (outgoing), 1969-1972 (Box 34, Folder 505)
    - Warren, Robert Penn (husband), 1951-1958 (Box 34, Folder 506-512)
    - Warren, Robert Penn (outgoing), undated (Box 34, Folder 513)
    - Warren, Rosanna (daughter), 1966-1983 (Box 34, Folder 514-516)
    - Warren, Rosanna, 1966-1983 (Box 35, Folder 517-531)
    - Warren, Rosanna, 1966-1983 (Box 36, Folder 532-540)
    - Warren, Rosanna (outgoing), 1966-1968 (Box 36, Folder 541-544)
    - Washington Post, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 545-546)
    - Welty, Eudora, 1978, undated (Box 37, Folder 547)
    - Wescott, Glenway, 1941, undated (Box 37, Folder 548)
    - Wesleyan University Press, 1969 December 8 (Box 37, Folder 549)
    - Wilder, Thornton, 1976, undated (Box 37, Folder 550)
    - Wright, Stuart, 1984 (Box 37, Folder 551)
    - Wyner, Yehudi, 1977-1982 (Box 37, Folder 552)
    - Yaddo (Artist's colony), 1968-1974 (Box 37, Folder 553)
    - The Yale Review, 1968, 1984 (Box 37, Folder 554)
    - Yale University. Library, 1977 June 17 (Box 37, Folder 555)
    - "Z" General, 1937-1975 (Box 37, Folder 556)
    - First name only, 1938-1974 (Box 37, Folder 557-558)
    - Unidentified, 1937, 1966 (Box 37, Folder 559)
    - Unidentified (outgoing), undated (Box 37, Folder 560)
  - Third Party Correspondence
    - Babbidge, Homer, 1975 March 4 (Box 37, Folder 561)
    - Clark, Eunice, 1925 April 22 (Box 37, Folder 562)
    - Clark, John E., 1876 July 4 (Box 37, Folder 563)
    - Corry, Andrew, 1979 November 29 (Box 37, Folder 564)
    - Gallup, Donald, 1977 (Box 37, Folder 565)
    - Phelps, Mr. and Mrs. Charles Henry (from Eunice Clark), 1931 (Box 37, Folder 566)
    - "Santa", undated (Box 37, Folder 567)
    - "Grandma Smith" (from Eleanor Phelps), [circa 1905] (Box 37, Folder 568)
    - Wald, Alan, 1974 November 18 (Box 37, Folder 569)
    - Warren, Gabriel, 1965-1984 (Box 37, Folder 570)
    - Warren, Robert Penn, 1972, undated (Box 37, Folder 571)
    - Warren, Rosanna, 1958-1968, undated (Box 37, Folder 572-574)
      Includes letters from Katherine Anne Porter, Robert Penn Warren, J.R.R. Tolkien, and others
  - Correspondence Relating to Writings
    - Baldur's Gate, 1970-1971 (Box 38, Folder 575-576)
    - Bitter Box, 1946 (Box 38, Folder 577)
      Includes correspondence from Elizabeth Ames and Mary Beard
    - Dr. Heart, 1974-1975 (Box 38, Folder 578)
      Includes correspondence from Robert Brustein
    - Eyes, Etc., 1977 (Box 38, Folder 579-580)
    - Gloria Mundi, 1979-1980 (Box 38, Folder 581)
      Includes correspondence from Saul Bellow and J.D. McClatchy
    - Oysters of Locmariaquer, 1962-1988 (Box 38, Folder 582-588)
    - Rome and a Villa, 1953-1975 (Box 38, Folder 589)
- Other Papers, 1881-1988; Series III; 1.05; (3 boxes)
  Arranged alphabetically by material type.
  Other papers include college papers, journals, notebooks, printed ephemera, and other miscellaneous material.
  - Awards and certificates, 1968-1984, undated (Box 39, Folder 590-592)
  - Box lists, [circa 1988] (Box 39, Folder 593)
  - Clippings, 1935-1985, undated (Box 39, Folder 594)
  - College papers, 1934, undated (Box 40, Folder 595-599)
  - Empty envelopes and folders, 1953-1974, undated (Box 40, Folder 600)
  - Memo [by Mr. Hardisty?], undated (Box 40, Folder 601)
  - Henry Wadsworth Longfellow's quill pen, [1881] (Box 40, Folder 602)
  - Jewelry, undated (Box 40, Folder 603)
  - Journals, 1933-1976 (Box 40, Folder 604-607)
  - Medical records, 1959 July 17 (Box 40, Folder 608)
  - Notebooks and notes, undated (Box 40, Folder 609-612)
  - Photographs, 1975, undated (Box 40, Folder 613)
  - Printed ephemera, 1935-1984, undated (Box 41, Folder 614-618)
  - String, undated (Box 41, Folder 619)
- Oversize, 1933-1988; 8.19; (10 boxes)
  - Publicity and reviews for Baldur's Gate (In Series I), 1970 (Box 42, Folder 620)
  - Book jacket design for Dr. Heart (In Series I), undated (Box 42, Folder 621)
  - Reviews for Dr. Heart (In Series I), 1975 (Box 42, Folder 622)
  - Reviews of Eyes, Etc. (In Series I), 1977-1978, undated (Box 42, Folder 623)
  - Reviews of Ostyers of Locmariaquer (In Series I), 1964-1965 (Box 42, Folder 624)
  - Book jacket design for Rome and a Villa (In Series I), 1974 August 7 (Box 42, Folder 625)
  - Galley proof of excerpt of Rome and a Villa (In Series I), 1974 (Box 42, Folder 626)
  - Background materials for introduction to 1975 edition of Rome and a Villa (In Series I), 1956-1974, undated (Box 42, Folder 627)
  - Publicity and reviews of Rome and a Villa (In Series I), 1952-1983, undated (Box 42, Folder 628)
  - Galley proof of excerpt from Tamrart (In Series I), undated (Box 42, Folder 629)
  - Draft of Gloria Mundi (In Series I), undated (Box 43, Folder 630)
  - Drafts of Eyes, Etc. (In Series I), 1976-1977 (Box 44, Folder 631)
  - Galley proof of Oysters of Locmariaquer (In Series I), 1964 February 10 (Box 45, Folder 632)
  - Galley proof of Oysters of Locmariaquer (In Series I), [1964] (Box 46, Folder 633)
  - Miscellaneous galley sheets of Oysters of Locmariaquer (In Series I), 1964 February (Box 47, Folder 634)
  - Page proof of Oysters of Locmariaquer (In Series I), 1964 March 9 (Box 48, Folder 635)
  - Galley proof of Rome and a Villa (In Series I), undated (Box 49, Folder 636)
  - Printed version of "Angel of Devastation" (In Series I), 1966 January 6 (Box 50, Folder 637)
  - Printed version of "Audobon: The Last Days of Nature" (In Series I), 1964 (Box 50, Folder 638)
  - Printed version of "Bad Housekeeping" (In Series I), 1969 (Box 50, Folder 639)
  - Printed version and galley proof of "Berenson's Last Years" (In Series I), 1964 March 5 (Box 50, Folder 640)
  - Printed version of "Brittany: Dragon Country" (In Series I), 1964 (Box 50, Folder 641)
  - Printed version of "The Cabinet of Dr. Kafka" (In Series I), 1938 February 2 (Box 50, Folder 642)
  - Printed version of "Commonweal or Common Woe?" (In Series I), 1964 July 9 (Box 50, Folder 643)
  - Printed version of "Friendships of a Lifetime" (In Series I), 1981 July 26 (Box 50, Folder 644)
  - Envelope for "Monday we Change our Clothes" (In Series I), 1988 August 16 (Box 50, Folder 645)
  - Printed version of "Speaking of Books" (In Series I), undated (Box 50, Folder 646)
  - Printed version of unidentified work (In Series I), 1933 November (Box 50, Folder 647)
  - Printed version of "The Ballad of Barnaby" by W.H. Auden (In Series II), 1972 (Box 50, Folder 648)
  - Clipping from Rosanna Warren correspondence (In Series II), 1971 July 31 (Box 50, Folder 649)
  - Correspondence from Yehudi Wyner (In Series II), undated (Box 50, Folder 650)
  - Clipping from third party correspondence to Rosanna Warren (In Series II), 1962 October 7 (Box 50, Folder 651)
  - Clippings from correspondence relating to Eyes, Etc. (In Series II), 1977 October 30 (Box 51, Folder 652)
  - Clippings from correspondence relating to Oysters of Locmariaquer (In Series II), 1964-1965 (Box 51, Folder 653)
  - Awards (In Series III), 1965-1984 (Box 51, Folder 654)
  - Clippings (In Series III), 1935-1985, undated (Box 51, Folder 655-656)
  - Empty envelopes and folders (In Series III), 1953-1974, undated (Box 51, Folder 657)
  - Printed ephemera (In Series III), undated (Box 51, Folder 658)
- Restricted Fragile Papers, 0.84; (2 boxes)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Writings (In Series I) (Box 52, Folder 659-683)
  - Writings (In Series I) (Box 53, Folder 684-697)
  - Correspondence (In Series II) (Box 53, Folder 698-736)
  - Other Papers (In Series III) (Box 53, Folder 737-739)